Finding Aid for Hutchins family papers, 1837-1951
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Hutchins family papers 1837-1951
Hutchins family.
4 linear feet, 2 oversize volumes, and 1 oversize folder
851509 Aa 2; AC; UAm
Allegan County, Michigan, family; correspondence, diaries, photographs, and business papers.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Evert O. Hutchins (donor no. 3788 )
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Hutchins family were early settlers to Allegan County, Michigan. Members of the family were involved in fruit farming and in the development of the Saugatuck and Ganges Telephone Company.
The collection consists of family correspondence, genealogical materials pertaining to the history of the Hutchins and Robertson families, miscellaneous writings of Henry Hudson Hutchins, papers concerning the family's fruit growing interests, and the development of the Saugatuck and Ganges Telephone Co. The collection is of significance for materials relating to the history of Allegan County, Michigan.
Subjects:
Agriculture--Michigan--Allegan County.; Allegan County (Mich.); Ganges (Mich.); Saugatuck (Mich.); Saugatuck and Ganges Telephone Company.; Telephone--Michigan--Allegan County.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Bicycles and tricycles.; Dwellings--Michigan--Fennville.; Farming.; Fennville (Mich.); Fennville (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Ganges (Mich.); Hunting--Michigan.; Hutchins family.; Lumber industry.; Recreation.; Women.
Contributors:
Hutchins, Evert O. (Evert Olney), 1890-; Hutchins, Henry Hudson, 1853-1933.; Robertson family.
Genre Terms:
Albums.; Drawings.; Photographs.; Tintypes.
- Family papers
  - Correspondence, 1920-1925, of Henry H., Harry, Lora, Lee, Samuel, Edward and Ira Hutchins (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, and diaries, 1910-1915, of Lee Hutchins (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1890-1900, with Dr. Brunson, Blackman, A.D. Goodrich, and D.S. Morgan and Company. (Box 1)
  - Business and miscellaneous correspondence of Henry Hutchins (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1920-1930, about the history of Allegan and Pier Cove, Michigan; also genealogy (Box 1)
  - Correspondence concerning Saugatuck and Ganges Telephone Company, 1892-1900 (Box 2)
    (Topics iclude an automobile collision and insurance settlement; agriculture, 1885-1930; fruit sorting and packaging; marketing and poultry)
  - Newspaper clippings concerning Singapore (Box 2)
  - Notes, pamphlets, and clippings concerning the American Legion, including notes of Henry Hutchins when he was a commander (Box 2)
  - Diaries and notes, 1880-1925, of Henry Hutchins (Box 3)
  - Family photographs, 2 folders (Box 3)
    (see also oversize photographs UAm)
  - Photograph albums, 2 volumes (Box 3)
  - Scrapbooks, 2 volumes (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1896-1928 and 1952 (Box 3)
  - Genealogical data on the Hutchins and Robertson families (Box 3)
  - Notebooks, 1843-1869, containing family correspondence and genealogical materials relating primarily to the Hutchins and Robertson families of Allegan County, Michigan, 2 volumes; (The volumes were compiled by Evert O. Hutchins in 1951.) (Box 4)
  - Notebook, undated, entitled "Genealogical Records and Historical Writings of Henry Hudson Hutchins" (Box 4)
    (include copies of newspaper articles, 1919, entitled "Pioneer Days in Western Allegan County"
  - Scrapbook, 1837-1942, of Harrison A. Harrison (Volume 1)
    ( include family photographs, drawings of family members, and memorabilia)
- Saugatuck and Ganges Telephone Company
  - Scrapbook, 1902-1905 (Volume 2)
    (Include drawings, financial statements, reports, lists of subscribers, etc.)
  - Ledgers and journals, 1903-1906 (Box 4)